Over a million of them shine with a blue light
靑く輝く 幾千万の 푸르게 빛나는 몇천만개의
The shards of love have scattered
愛のかけらが ちりばめられた 사랑의 조각들이 흩어져 있어
It's brewing in this world
この 地球(ほし)の中 蠢く 이 지구 안에 휘몰아치는
A storm that you'll confront
嵐に向かう 폭풍우로 달려가는
And because I believe in you
君を信じたから 너를 믿으니까
I'm not afraid of anything
何も恐れないさ 아무것도 두렵지 않아
GO WITH ME Exkaiser
GO WITH ME エクスカイザ-！ GO WITH ME 엑스카이저!
Courage and friendship
勇氣と友情！ 용기와 우정!
That moment when we join our strength GATHER WAY
力 あわせた その 時 GATHER AWAY 힘을 합치는 그순간 GATHER AWAY
GO WITH ME Exkaiser
GO WITH ME エクスカイザ-！ GO WITH ME 엑스카이저!
I'd almost forgotten it
忘れかけていた！ 잊고 있었던
The fiery burning and important PASSIONATE feeling in my heart
熱く 燃える 大切な PASSIONATE この 胸に 뜨겁게 불타는 소중한 PASSIONATE내 가슴에!
The mysterious and vast universe.
신비하고 광대한 우주 神秘で廣大な宇宙... 성우:山寺宏一야마데라 코이치
In this universe exists the evil life forms, the space pirates Geisters
이 우주에 깃든 この宇宙に巢食う
who've invaded Earth in order to obtain the treasures of mankind.
인류의 보물을 노리고 지구로 잠입했다 人類の寶を狙って地球に潛入した
However, in front of the Geisters who use destruction and plunder as they wish
하지만 파괴와 약탈을 일삼으며 しかし,破壞と略奪を
a hero appeared, who completely stood in their way.
과감하게 막아내는 영웅이 있다 敢然と立ち塞がるヒ-ロ-がいた
He's the cosmic police, Exkaiser.
우주 경찰 엑스카이저다 宇宙警察エクスカイザ-である
This is the story of Brave Exkaiser and his friends, who fight against evil all around the universe.
이것은 우주에 퍼지고 있는 악과 싸우는 これは,宇宙に蔓延る惡と戰う
Our Sunken Ship Expedition Party
第６話　ボクら沈沒船たんけん隊 第６話　우리는 침몰선 탐험대 1990/3/10
Concerning our previous announcement...
방금 전의 발표에 의하면
The undersea volcano ceased trembling and has returned to a dormant state.
걱정했던 해저 화산의 재분화의 공포가 사라져
Therefore, there is no need for any alarm.
모레부터의 선박의 항해가 허가되었습니다
Really? I was sure it would have blown...
뭐야! 대폭발 할거라고 생각했더니만..
No, it's good it didn't blow.
아니, 폭발하지 않아서 다행이지
The tickets would have been such a waste.
표를 못 써먹을 뻔 했거든
Tickets?
표요? (*けん/켄-券:입장, 승차권의 표)
I have these tickets for a submarine exploration trip.
관광 잠수함 표를 얻어왔단다
-Wanna go? -All right!
갈래?  / 신난다!
Isn't that great?
좋겠네
Then, why don't you take Fuuko with you--
그럼 후우코 누나한테 데려...
Forget it!
무슨 말씀하시는 거예요!
I couldn't care less about a childish submarine exploration trip...
관광잠수함이라니.. 유치하잖아요
Well? Why don't you take Kotomi-chan with you?
어때? 코토미한테 가자고 하는게?
Isn't that perfect for children's date like yours?
애들 데이트에는 아주 딱이잖아?
Children?
애라고?
Next in the news,
그럼 이어서 다음 뉴스입니다
the submarine sightseeing tours have discovered a sunken ship along their course.
관광 잠수함의 유람코스에서 침몰선이 발견되었습니다
Starting tomorrow, regular trips will allow sightseers to visit their site.
오늘 아침 운항 재개에 앞서 예비 조사 중에 발견된 것입니다
The ship was sunk deep into the ocean floor, and revealed itself after the ground shifted by
해저 심해에 가라앉아 있었으나
being pushed to the near sea, according to the specialists.
근해로 밀려 올라온 것으로 전문가들은 보고 있습니다
It's at least 300 years old, and from its shape, there is speculation that it is definitely a pirate's.
작지만 300년이상 된 선박으로 그 형태로 봐서는
And soon, people will be able to ride the romantic dream of a pirate ship.
어쨌든 사람들의 로맨틱한 꿈을 실은 해적선 (*小杉十郞太/코스기 쥬로타/ 프테라가이스터(익룡))
We sure look forward to whatever treasures they uncover on the site.
어떤 보물이 발굴될지 기대됩니다
I've changed my mind!
아! 나 그냥 갈래요
Nope!
잡았다!
Isn't it great that you're not a kid anymore, sis?
누나도 애라면 좋았을 걸 그랬지?
I get to see the sunken ship~! See ya!
가까이에서 침몰선을 볼 수 있었는데~
Damn...
에이~!
It's at least 300 years old, and from its shape, there is speculation that it is definitely a pirate's.
작지만 300년이상 된 선박으로 그 형태로 봐서는
And soon, people will be able to ride the romantic dream of a pirate ship.
어쨌든 사람들의 로맨틱한 꿈을 실은 해적선
We sure look forward to whatever treasures they uncover on the site.
어떤 보물이 발굴될지 기대됩니다
What's a sunken ship?
침몰선이 뭐야? 沈沒船って何だ?
You mean you don't know what a sunken ship is?
야 너는 침몰선도 모르냐? お前,沈沒船もしらねえのか
A sunken ship is, uh...
침몰선이라는 건 말야..아..그게... 沈沒船っていうのはだなあ,ええと...
It's a ship that sunk during a sea voyage!
항해중에 가라앉은 배야 航海中に沈んだ船のことだ
I was about to explain that, so shut up!
내가 지금 설명해 줄라고 했어,이 자식아! ああっ,俺が今說明しようと思ったのに.. このおっ..!
Ass! You hurt me!
이 자식아, 아프잖아! てめえ痛てえじゃねえか
What the hell are you doing!?
뭐 하는 짓이냐구!
Get off me right now!
남의 말을 들을...
Shut up! Shut up, shut up, shut up!
시끄러~~!!!시끄러 시끄러 시끄러~~!! うるさ~~い!!うるさいうるさいうるさい!!
Thunder Geist, go and steal this sunken ship!
썬더 가이스터,이 침몰선을 빼앗아와라 (*サンダ-ガイスト)
Thunder Geist!
썬더 가이스터? サンダ-ガイスト?
What's a sunken ship?
침몰선이 뭐야? 沈沒船って何だ? (*썬더가이스터-브론트 사우루스형 로봇)
That idiot is friggin' useless!
저 멍청이! 도대체 도움이 안된다니까! こんなボケ! 役にたたねえぜ!
Let us take care of it!
일은 우리한테 맡겨라 仕事なら俺たちにまかせな!
Idiot...?
멍청이?  난 멍청이가 아냐! ボケ..? 俺はボケじゃねえ!
Thunder Geist, steal this sunken ship now!
썬더 가이스터, 이 침몰선을 빼앗아와라
If you follow the tour submarine, it will lead you to the sunken ship.
침몰선은 관광잠수함의 뒤를 밟으면 찾아낼 수 있을거다
... Is what lord Dino Geist said.
..라고 다이노 가이스터님이 말씀하셨다
Wait!
기다려
Take this Energy Box with you..
이 에너지 박스를 가져가라
Place it on the lighthouse that should be by the shore or something and...
버튼을 눌러서 근처 등대에라도 장착해서...
Leave it to me.
맡겨둬!
Hey, let me explain how to--!
야, 사용방법을...!
What an ass!
뭐 저런 놈이 다 있어!
That sunken pirate ship is so romantic!
해적선이라니 로맨틱하다~
Actually, Kotomi-chan...
코토미, 실은 말야..
Kotomi-chan, care to come with me on my own submarine to look for sunken treasure tomorrow?
코토미, 내일 우리집 잠수함으로 ボクのうちの?水艦で海賊船の
Your own submarine?
우리집 잠수함?
That's right.
그래
No thanks.
난 됐어
W- why?
왜~애?
I think it's far more fun to dream up what kind of treasures are down there.
난 어떤 보물이 있을까 どんな寶物があるか
Looking for it myself sounds a little boringn.
진짜 보고나면 시시해 질 것 같아
R- really?
그..그래?
I guess Kotomi-chan wouldn't come along.
코토미는 안가겠구나
Ah! Are those tickets for the submarine tour!?
아~그거 관광 잠수함 입장권이잖아?
I want to go, too!
나도 가고 싶어! (私も行きたい)
But you just said that you didn't want to see the treasure.
코토미는 보물같은 건 보고싶지 않다고 하지 않았어?
The treasure is one thing, but the pirate ship is another!
보물말이야!
If I see the pirate ship, I could imagine the treasure better!
해적선을 보면 海賊船を見ると
Isn't it romantic?
로맨틱하잖아~? ロマンチックじゃない~?
Alright! That's right, it's super romantic!
됐다! 그래, 로맨틱하지?
Yup!
음!
Kotomi-chan, would you like to go with me tomorrow?
코토미, 괜찮으면 내일 같이 갈래?
I can?
정말!
No way...!
이럴수가~!
It sounds like fun, Kouta.
코우타, 즐거워 보이는구나 觀光潛水艦 フリッビ―號 관광잠수함 플리피호
I'm so excited thinking about what kind of treasures are down there!
왜냐면, 어떤 보물이 있을까 상상하는 것만으로도 가슴이 두근두근 해지거든
Why does just thinking about it make you excited?
어째서 상상하는 것만으로도 가슴이 두근두근 한거지?
Eh? Uh... that's because...
에..그건..?
Because it's romantic!
로맨틱하거든~
Romantic?
로맨틱?
It's romantic to imagine things!
이렇게 저렇게 상상할 수 있다는 게 로맨틱하잖아?
That's why.
그래서 그런거야...
Romantic...
로맨틱...음...
Install it on something and push the button, he said.
버튼을 눌러서 장착하랬지?
Uh, what's install?
아? 장착이 뭐지?
Ah, whatever.
아~ 뭐 알게 뭐야
I'm off!
다녀오겠습니다~
Kouta sure is happy today.
코우타가 평소보다 기운이 솟는 것 같은데?
Because he's going on a date with Kotomi-chan.
코토미랑 데이트한다고 했거든요
A date, eh?
데이트한다고?
Mama! It's been a while since we've gone for a drive!
여보! 우리도 오랜만에 드라이브나 갈까?
Oh, how wonderful!
어머, 근사해요!
Let me finish this up!
바로 준비하고 올게요
Hey, wait a second there!
아! 잠깐만요!
If you two leave, what am I supposed to do?
엄마 아빠가 외출하고 나면 난 어쩌라고요?
I'm supposed to sit at home alone on a Sunday?
일요일인데 나만 집보고 있으라고요?
You don't have a boyfriend, Fuuko?
후우코는 남자친구 없니?
Why are you saying!?
갑자기 그건 왜 물어요...
I've got two or three!
남자 친구야. 둘셋은 있다구요 ボ-イフレンドの二人や三人いるわよ
Then today is officially Date Day!
그럼, 오늘은 데이트의 날로 정하자
Everyone go on a date!
모두 데이트하는 거야
Shall we get going, Papa?
자, 나갈까요, 여보~
Of course, mama.
그러자구, 여보~
If I had even one boyfriend, I wouldn't have even said a thing!
남자 친구가 하나라도 있었다면 걱정도 안할걸요
Well, you're a little fat and furry, but I guess you'll have to do today.
좀 살은 찌고 털은 많지만 오늘은 너로 위안을 삼아야겠다
Yahoo!
야호!
All right! It's the submarine!
신난다! 잠수함이다!
Let's go, Kotomi-chan!
가자,코토미
Huh?
에?
Hi! Good morning.
애들아, 안녕?
Takumi-kun!
타쿠미!
With those clothes... Don't tell me...
그 복장...혹시...
You wouldn't be getting on this submarine, would you?
너 설마 이 잠수함에 탈려고...
I thought it would be interesting to witness the kind of fun your kind experience.
가끔은 너희같은 서민들의 즐거움을 맛보는 것도 재밌을 것 같다고 생각했거든
Now, get rid of this guy and come along with me.
자, 저런 녀석은 두고 어서 가자
Well well! If it isnn't Kouta-kun!
어이, 코우타 아니냐?
Oh...
이크...
You're getting on this submarine tour as well?
코우타 너도 관광 잠수함에 탈거니?
Yeah... and you?
네, 토쿠다 아저씨도요?
I'm for work. I'm reporting it!
취재가는 거야, 취재
We're departing! Please board if you're departing!
출발하겠습니다! 타실분은 서둘러 주십시요!
We shouldn't be standing here. Let's get on!
어물어물하다간 늦겠구나
Come on!
어서 가자!
Hey! Wait!
잠깐! 같이 가요~
It sure is pretty.
아름답구나
Wouldn't you say, Kouta-kun?
그렇지, 코우타?
Tokuda-san, aren't you working?
토쿠다 아저씨, 취재 안하실 거예요?
Oh, oops!
아, 그렇지!
Say, if you really want a nice scoop, the front window is the best!
있잖아요, 특종이라면 창가쪽에서 잘 보일 걸요?
I'll take your seat!
바꿔드릴까요?
No thanks.
그러면 미안하지
I'm perfectly fine here.
난 여기서도 충분하니까
Look at that, Kouta-kun!
아, 저기 봐, 코우타!
That's the sunken ship!
저게 침몰선인가봐
I found it.
찾았다!
Captain, something is approaching us.
함장님, 뭔가가 접근해오고 있습니다
What?
뭐?
All right! I'm definitely gonna have a scoop today!
좋아! 오늘이야말로 특종을 잡을 수 있겠군
Huh? It seems that the volcano here has a dinosaur from long time ago!
음? 어디 있었지?
You mean a Brontosaurus?
브론트 사우루스라고 말씀하셨으면 좋겠네요
The Brontosaurus, from the Jurassic era.
쥬라기의 브론트 사우루스
Don't you know anything? And you work for a newspaper at that...
신문기자라면 그 정도는 알고 계셔야죠~
Huh? There is no way it would be there...
에? 그런게 있을 리 없을 것 같은데..
A dinosaur!
으...공룡이다!
A Geister!
가이스터야!
You're in my way!
방해 된다구!
H- Heavy...!
으...무거워...
I can't take this by my own.
이건 도저히 내 힘만으로는 안되겠군
How nostalgic...
그리워지네요
Remember this place?
여기 기억해요?
Huh?
에?
Aww, did you forget?
정말이지~ 잊은 거에요?
I'm sorry.....
미안
I'm lying! How could I ever forget?
장난이야 잊었을 리가 없잖아
This is where we had our first date!
당신하고 첫데이트한 곳이니까
Oh, papa!
참.. 당신도~
Mama! That lighthouse is moving!
여보, 등대가 돌아다니고 있어
Another little lie!
또 장난치는 거죠?
I guess so!
맞아, 장난한거야
The Geisters are on the move.
가이스터가 움직이기 시작했다!
Kouta, is anything wrong over there?
코우타, 네가 있는 곳은 별일 없나?
Kouta! Kouta!
코우타! 코우타! 무슨 일이냐?
Exkaiser!
엑스카이저!
The Geisters have moved out. Did anything happen there?
가이스터가 움직이기 시작했다! 그쪽은 아무 이상 없나?
It's over now! A Geister appeared and...
끝이야! 가이스터가 나타나서...
Holy moly! The Geisters are trying to make off with the sunken ship!
큰일났어! 가이스터가 침몰선을 가져 가려고 해!
What?
뭐?
Don't worry about it. I'm on my way!
걱정하지 마라 지금 바로 가겠다
Mama, where should we go next--
여보 다음 어디로 갈까?
Huh? I'm sure we parked here!
어? 확실히 여기에...
Change, Exkaiser!
チェ-ンジ!  エクスカイザ ! Change! Exkaiser ! 체인지! 엑스카이저 !
-What just happened? -What is going on?
대체 무슨 일이 있었던 거야?/ 무슨 일이 벌어진 거야?
My glasses... Where are my glasses?
안경... 내 안경...
My camera, my camera.... I can't find my camera!
카메라 카메라... 카메라가 없어...
Kotomi-chan! Kotomi-chan!
코토미 코토미!
Kotomi-chan, are you all right?
코토미 괜찮아?
I think I'm fine...
괜찮은 것 같아
Ah! Kouta-kun! The sunken ship--!
아, 코우타! 침몰선이!
Don't worry. It'll be fine!
괜찮아, 걱정 안해도 돼
How do you know?
어떻게 알아?
I... I just have a feeling it will!
그..그런 기분이 들어..
Hold it, Geister!
멈춰라, 가이스터
Spike Cutter!
スパイクカッタ-! Spike cutter! 스파이크 커터!
You again?
또 네 놈이구나!
Geister!
가이스터!
You scoundrels who ruin the romance of others shall not be forgiven!
사람들의 로망을 짓밟는 너희 악당들을! 人人のロマンを破ろうとする貴樣達惡黨を
It's the defender of justice!
정의의 아군이야! (正義の身方)
We were waiting for you!
기다리고 있었어요!
-Kouta-kun! -Yeah!
코우타! 응!
Shaddup!
간다!
Flaming Nova!
フレ-ミングノヴァ! Flaming Noba! 플레이밍 노바!
What power!
가공할 만한 힘이다!
Impact Flash!
インパクトフラッシュ! Impact Flash! 임팩트 플래쉬!
Alright!
해치웠다!
I'm pissed!
나 화났다!
What's that?
뭐지?
This must be an eruption! It's about to erupt!
이..이건 분화다! 분화하기 시작했어!
Shit! I won't forget this!
젠장, 기억하고 있으라구!
Running away!?
도망가는 거냐?
Kouta!
코우타!
King Loader!
キング-ロ-ダ- King Loader 킹 로더!
Giant Fusion, King Exkaiser!
巨大合體 キングエクスカイザ 거대합체 킹엑스카이저!
Kaiser Shot!
カイザ-ショット ! Kaiser shot ! 카이저 샷 !
We're done for!
이젠 끝장이야 추락해서 여기서 죽을 거야
Kouta-kunn!
-코우타! -코토미, 정신차려
Don't worry! I'm sure we'll be saved!
괜찮을 거야, 분명히 살 수 있어
Do your best, Exkaiser!
힘내, 엑스카이저!
I need more strength!
힘이...
Kaiser Sword!
カイザ-ソ-ド Kaiser Sword 카이저 소드!
Thunder Flash!
サンダ-フラッシュ! Thunder Flash! 썬더 플래쉬!
Kouta!
코우타!
The treasures from the sunken ship!
침몰선의 보물이...!
It's treasure! It's treasure!
보물이다 보물!
It's so pretty!
예쁘다~
I've never been on such a romantic voyage!
이렇게 로맨틱한 경험은 처음이야
It's all thanks to you, Kouta-kun!
코우타 덕분이야
Nah, I didn't do anythingg!
뭘...나도...
Thanks, Exkaiser!
고마워, 엑스카이저!
That sure is strange...
이상하네
I'm sure I parked it around here...
분명히 이 근처에 세워뒀는데...
Papa, look over there.
여보! 저기 봐요!
Well, now that is indeed strange!
이거 참 이상하네~
It wasn't there when we looked before.
아까 찾아봤을 땐 없더니만...
Papa, it's all good since it came back!
여보~ 돌아왔으니까 됐어요 かえって良かったじゃない~
We got to sit here together on this memorable spot.
추억의 장소에서 계속 함께 있을 수 있었잖아요
That's right!
그것도 그렇구만
Faraway wind carries your dream
遙かな 風が 夢を 運んで 아득한 바람이 꿈을 가져와
What could you discover from this excited feeling
ときめく 事に 何を 見つけるの 설레이는 일에서 무엇을 찾아낼까
Dreams get bigger strongly and fast
强く 早く ふくらむ 夢に 강하고 빠르게 부풀어 오르는 꿈에
Don't forget to be who you are
自分らしさ 忘れずに 자신다운 모습을 잊지 말고
Embrace your enthusiastic heart
夢中に なれる 心 抱きしめ 정열적인 마음 꼭 껴안고
And try walking that path
その 道を 步いてみてね 그 길을 걸어가 보는거야
The Jet Coaster, the Coffee Cup, and the House of Illusion!
ジェットコ-スタ-に コ-ヒ-カップに觀覽車
I'm sure you've all gone on them!
みんなも 乘ったことあるよね
The amusement park where Kotomi-chan and I had our first date suddenly disappeared!
ボクがコトミちゃんと初めてデ-トした思い出の 遊園地が突然消えちゃった!
Would the Geisters steal such a thing?
ガイスタ-が 訓練用に盜んだんだって!?
Ahhh! What are we gonna do!? Everyone's memorable spot will be torn to pieces!
ええ~どうしよう, みんなの思い出が目茶目茶だよう!
On the next episode of Brave Exkaiser,
次回,勇者エクスカイザ-
Danger Turns Round and Round at the Amusement Park!
"遊園地でキケンがぐるぐる!"
Is there an alien in your home, too?
君んちにも宇宙人,いる？